pv-magazine.com 2019-10-15

# Privacy Policy – pv magazine International

## Data protection declaration

pv magazine takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. We design our data processing systems with the aim of collecting, processing and using only as much personal data as is necessary to enable the rational and economically efficient use of our products and services.

You can find out below when this data is stored as you use our website and how we use this data. We have implemented technical and organizational measures to ensure that we comply with data protection regulations. More particularly, our products and services are subject to the provisions of the Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (German Federal Data Protection Act, BDSG) and the Teledienstedatenschutzgesetz (Teleservices Data Protection Act, TDDS

#### Personal data

Personal data is information that can be used to ascertain your identity. This includes your name and address details, for example. It does not include information that cannot be directly associated with particular persons.

Our website can generally be used without requiring you to disclose your identity. If you wish to participate in one of our personalized services, you will be asked separately to provide the data that is necessary for the provision of that service. It is entirely up to you to choose to participate in these services and to give us the necessary data.  
We store your details on specially protected servers in Germany. Only the necessary number of specially authorized persons has access to these servers. These persons are involved in the technical, commercial or editorial supervision of the servers.

In conjunction with your access of our website, data which may enable identification is stored on our server for backup purposes – for example, IP address, date, time, pages visited. However, we do not use this data in any personalized way.  
For the evaluation and continuous improvement of the quality of our website we carry out statistical analyses of access to our web pages. In some cases, this also involves the use of counter graphics that appear on some pages of our site. However, the data obtained in this way is strictly anonymous and does not enable any inference of the user’s personal data.

Your data is never used to create user profiles – of whatever kind.

#### Passing on personal data to third parties

As a rule, we do not pass on personal data to third parties. In particular, we do not forward data to third parties for promotional purposes.

In so far as you use personalized services (such as our shop), however, it may be necessary to collect personal data and pass this on to third parties for the purposes of implementing and handling the provision of the service. This data shall be stored and forwarded only to the extent required to process your order. To this end, you are required to submit an express declaration of consent when you fill out the respective order form. Moreover, third parties to whom your data is forwarded in the context of order processing are also bound by the statutory regulations for the treatment of personal data.  
In so far as we are under obligation by law or by court order to do so, we shall forward data to the respective agencies that are entitled to receive this information.

#### Contact forms

To improve our products and services and to facilitate the shipment of goods, you are given the option of answering questions relating to our products via the contact forms. You are under no obligation to answer the questions. You may also send us your inquiry and obtain our products and services without providing additional information on the forms. The data you supply will be used to improve the services we offer you and is stored together with your personal data. We store only the data you voluntarily provide us with and do not pass this information on to third parties.

#### Right to cancel

If you have sent us personal data, you may instruct us to delete it at any time. Data held for billing and accounting purposes shall not be affected by cancellation or by a request for deletion.

#### Minors

Persons under 18 years of age should not send any personal data to us without the permission of their parents or guardians. We do not require any personal data from minors, do not collect such data and do not forward such data to third parties.

#### Links to other websites

In so far as our website contains links to the offerings of other service providers, we cannot guarantee that these third party websites will comply with legal provisions. Nor do we accept any liability for their failure to do so. Please consult providers’ data protection declarations at the respective websites to find out what data protection standards are applicable in each case.

#### Changes

This information is subject to the respective legal situation and may therefore need to be modified.

_October 17, 2016_
